So good morning everyone again. Um, Uh, as you can see my
screen, I've put this, um, this quiz,
right? This quiz is the one which will be due this Wednesday,
so on April 1st. So I hope you will click the right
one because last week we have some students who clicked the wrong one,
and then, and then asked me to do it again.
So I said, OK, because if you have done one and I can't give you
the second attempt. Um, yeah, so make sure you're clicking the right one.
And we also have the next one, which is attaching to this
week's activity. Um, so don't, um, do this one,
I mean, before you should do, right? So this is due on
Wednesday this week, uh, which was based on the activity we have
been practicing last week, right? And then with this week,
we, we also have the workshop activity, um,
but because the, uh, it is a Friday, I think Friday is a
holiday. So we will upload a recording
um on Friday. So if you need to watch the recording,
please go through the recording place, right?
And then, and then you can watch the recording and you can do the activity.
However, The quiz will be due on next
Wednesday after the break week, which is 15th of April,
right, the 15th of April, right? So it's not rush.
Uh, you have some break week to catch up with the course,
right? So for students who haven't done the previous week and hasn't,
I mean, submitted. Um, yeah, please submit,
please submit, uh, 2.1, 2.2 as soon as possible.
2.2 is due this this Wednesday. And you can see the access code is
always pop up when you click those quiz,
right? Um, so that's for this week, which is due on
15th of April. And here is where you can find the recording.
I still got uh inquiry about where to find recording.
So clicking this collaborate and clicking this sign and you would see all the
recording here. So, normally with the lecture,
I rename them in week, and the workshop I also rename
them in week, OK, week 2, sorry.
Workshop week 2, workshop week 3, workshop week 4,
not yet, but, I will upload one later. Um,
so you can also see there might be a Wednesday workshop which is actually the same
content as week 3, like, sorry, workshop week 3
and Wednesday workshop week 3 because there's an actual workshop on
Wednesday, which was run by another tutor.
Um, it's actually for some, mm, some
people, women, um, only students who are
now employees, so which is a special workshop,
but the content are the same, right? So if you would like to watch what the tutor,
um, taught in that workshop, you, you're welcome to see them,
but I think the one, on Friday, Um, yeah,
was the one covering everything and was for this cohort,
right, for these online students. So, OK,
so this Wednesday one was probably uh involved more discussion and
also from those um fully employed the women students and,
yeah, in the special program 8032. So,
uh, I would suggest you watch the workshop on Friday.
OK. Um, yeah, so, so that's it
for the, for the uh recording. And then I
will.
Uh, yeah. Just close my window.
Now today, uh, what we will learn is this authentication,
which is one of the most important part for our uh
system design, right? So for this authentication protocol.
Um, I've put the hash algorithm and public key and private key authentication in my
pre-lecture recording. So if you haven't watched them,
please do watch them, right? And then, um,
it's part of our lecture study. So
all this week, we will learn all these basic
authentication protocols and then we will analyze password-based
authentication and try to identify the possible factors we can
use for authentication, which can be a more secured authentication
protocol, right, what are the factors we can use.
And I also wish you can know the difference and how to
evaluate this authentication protocol. OK.
So, And when we normally talk about authentication,
it's the very first um task for AAA
authentication. AAA, when we talk about AAA,
we mean authentication, authorization, and
accountability, right? So what these terms mean is normally we
have the first identification, uh, which is a person claims
to claims, um, an identity. And then the system would
authenticate whether that person is actually the one he
claims to be, right? And then authorization
or sometimes called access control more popularly and called access control,
right? So this is where a system would access
the right resources to grant the right
resources to those persons. To those subjects,
right? So you do this access control. And then finally,
which is accountability, uh, which means a system can record
a person a subject's action after logging.
So normally, um, you have the experience that you,
you log into your bank system, right? The bank shows what is your last time logging.
And maybe um the system itself also record what's the duration of
your last login, and every login, right?
And also what's the activity you have done,
uh, every time when you log into the bank system,
whether you did the transaction, whether you did the,
um, some saving, OK, so all that activity
will be recorded. So we call that system provides this
accountability. But of course, not every system would have to have
this accountability, um, because sometimes it's just not necessary.
Uh, and also it, it actually, um, create extra burden for
the system, right? He has to, uh, keep for every user,
he has to maintain those records for every user.
It's very resource intensive, right, for having this accountability.
So sometimes, and most times, a system is designed without accountability,
um, only has the very Uh, safe
authentication and authorization in the system.
OK. So, um, so now this week we'll talk about
authentication. Next week we'll talk about access control,
OK. So for the authentication, um, which in
definition, it is called this. Um, however,
the actual authentication doesn't always have to be a
client to authenticate authenticate himself to a server.
And we also have the server authenticate himself to a client.
So there's two-way authentication. Because sometimes when Amazon has to
authenticate himself to be Amazon, right?
So that's a server reports an identity to a client.
So we have two-way authentication happening in reality.
And the steps very easy. So, um, normally we
initiate and then the challenge, OK, who you are,
and then the client side, he probably will do some calculation or look up an
answer and can be look up his own ID or provide a password
or provide a one-time code, right, and then,
and then proof, right, send this proof. And then
the server will validate in his end, will check the proof
and then pass or fail, right? So this is the obvious steps.
And now we talk about the zones in authentication.
There's a zone 1, client zone, transmission zone,
zone 2, and the server zone, zone 3. Right,
when we design a good authentication protocol with which all these three
zones are considered, are covered very well,
and you have to consider a very good authentication protocol which
has all these zones very safe, right? So,
and then, OK, so then when we talk about the factors we can use for
authenticating. Um, we normally have all the three types of
factors, what you know, what you have, what you are.
So what you know means, OK, your ID, your password,
right? And what you have, which means your digital certificate,
for example, the server has some digital certificate,
right? Uh, like his password, sorry, his public key is
whatever, right, and certified by,
um, by another big security company, right?
So that's his digital certificate, right?
And then the client can believe that server is truly Amazon,
right? And then some, a one time pad OTP means
one time pad device which can be this client's coder,
right, and the bank coder. That's a type of one-time code
device, a one-time pad device. And what you are,
which means you physically, you have that fingerprint,
you have that certain eye scan result, OK,
retina scan or, or other face recognition,
that's what you are, right? So all these factors can be used for authentication.
And there has been some very matured authentication system,
but normally, and most time we talk about authentication design,
we actually uh can refer to some matured system.
We can also um design an authentication based on
our understanding of all these factors we can use,
right? OK. So first, let's see the first type of uh
factor, what you know. Um, at most times when we talk about what you
know, we actually, uh, always think about password,
OK? We try to prove a person is Alice if Alice
knows her password, right? So we use this password-based authentication.
It's a very popular authentication method.
It's very cheap to implement because it doesn't involve any
equipment like a bank coder, right? And it's
not secure. Because if it's a password-based
authentication, you can imagine if the password is saved in client
side and then, um, even if the user.
Doesn't give out, but the people can do brute force attack.
Right, or can um get this user to click some
email link and through phishing, right? And then this,
this client can click those links and can get his password leaked through
this uh link and also by brute force attack,
which means another attacker can try every
combination of the keyboard, OK, just to go through every type of
combination in the keyboard. Until he got the right
combination of the password, right, so we call that brute force attack.
So in zone one, there are such kind of attacking issues,
and in transmission zone, which is zone 2,
there's sniffing issue, right? Some person can steal the whole packets
sending to the server end. And in the server end,
there might be. Um, insider reading the password
file or some outsider attacker who can get through the system
and they can check all the passwords, right,
uh, and then it can be, uh, some dictionary attack,
so which means he can access to some password,
um, information and maybe do some, because English word,
uh, is in certain pattern. And then he probably can do a bit more
um guessing um on, on this password. So if it's
stored in plain password, and then he doesn't even have to do anything,
so he can probably see those passwords, right,
already. So which why we actually the password can definitely not be
a plain password go through this system.
Right, And then The password also not user
friendly because Um, there are so many different
passwords to remember, uh, for every different logging system.
And then that's why the people have come up with some solutions such as password manager.
Uh, you have heard this last pass and the one password which creates
extra. Um, encrypted, um, password and stored
locally in your computer and then they, they,
they save their key very safely, right? And when you have to access to your password
and they actually use that key to decrypt that password,
uh, for you so that you've got the right password,
um, to log into your system, right? So they save the password for you.
OK, so those commercial solutions to save or to,
to remember the password for you, you don't have to remember by yourself,
right? Um, but, but still people love passwords so much.
Um, the reason I think, very easy to understand,
right? So it's cheap, and the developer doesn't have to develop some new,
uh, equipment to, to, to, to, to use this password based
authentication. It's very interoperable and people just get
used, get used to it, right? So then because the
plain password is not a good solution, right,
we should never store and send plain password.
Then the encrypting password, encrypted password,
um, is not good either. Because the key can be stolen
and then, and then the password can be exposed if it's a symmetric
key encryption, right? So we encrypt the password and the key has
been shared between this client and server,
and server can decrypt the password and then check whether the password is the right one
stored in his server. And if it's the right one,
then he let this client go through the system.
However, the key can be stolen and all password can be
exposed, and the same password will be computed to the same ciphertext.
Um, then at least if Alice and Bob, they are using the same
password. And then after encrypting and this by reading these
ciphertext we we already know or Alice and Bob they are using the same password because
ciphertexts are the same right because encrypting the symmetric
encrypting is based on bit uh wise XOR
operation. Right, so if the original passwords are the same,
maybe the output would be the same, and also the password lengths can be,
um, can be leaked because the ciphertext would
normally be equal to this, um, password lengths,
right? So the encrypting, um, symmetric encrypting is
not a good solution, uh, which you can see.
Um, the hashing is a solution here. The hashing algorithm,
uh, would always generate the same length of output,
OK, for a different password input. So the
output would always be the same, right? So which is a hash results.
And then there's no key management required,
which means it's not based on the symmetric key.
So the server side, he does not have a key either,
right? A password is generated and a hash was passed to the server,
and server would check the hash results.
If it's the same as the one he stored in his end,
and he will allow this person to log in,
right? So there's no key management required here.
And which Uh, also means there's no clear
password readable by this server because hash function is
a one-way function, uh, as mentioned in my preelect recording.
It's a one-way function you can never derive or
mathematically from this age result back to what is
your PWD password there, right? So that's
the hashing can help. Right.
Um, so the benefits of hashing is when, when the
database which um stored all the hash results,
right, um, were compromised, but that would
not reveal the user's password, OK, and also it does
not have much extra overhead for storage because the
storage, um, when you store a password or when you store password hash and then the
results actually. Quite um similar, right?
So the, the, the memory required are very similar,
right, not much higher, um, and so there's not much
um extra overhead for storage and locking.
Um, but also it means, OK, some disadvantage here,
we can't recover the password for users who forget.
So if you're using some system 10 years ago,
which was based on, still based on that encrypted password.
So when you forget a password, and the system can use a key to
do a decryption and it can send back your password,
you still can see your original design of your password.
However, nowadays, the system does not
uh design and use that encrypted password anymore.
So they all use hashed password. So, because the hash function
is not reversible, so, which is why the
system cannot Do a reverse function calculation
and to do this, um, this can recover the password
for you. So what they do normally is ask you to create a new password,
right, and then they store the hashed results in the server and again,
so the system just doesn't know what's your original password.
Cannot recover your password? And the attacker could
create a A table of password hash to compare against the
database. What this means is actually, um,
instead of doing one-way function reversely,
what they do is they create a table, OK,
like this, so which includes a combination of all
different passwords, right, and the table can be very long.
And then if it's an MD5 hash used by a server,
right? By a system design, and then the server end can,
or not necessarily be a server end, it can be a hacker,
a third-party hacker, and he can maintain such a table
which has all hash results calculated based on
each different combination of the passwords.
And then he has this table maintained. And now you can imagine
if you happen to use a password.
Uh, like this 9 digit password, OK, which is
a very, very normal password. You happen to use that one.
And then when you pass the hash, OK, so you are passing that hash
result, right? 129, right? So
that hash result was passed to the system,
right. So the server end, the server end will check.
The results, sorry, um, my writing, it's uh it's not a
touchable screen so. So this hashed result
is actually this one, right? So these results,
this long digit was passed to the server end.
And then what server end is doing um is actually
check this hash result. If it's the same one,
and he will let you log into the system,
right? But the attacker, because the attacker has this whole table in
his end, he got the hash, stole the hash from this
transmission zone. And then after he got this hash results,
right, so this The attacker would
compare the got rehash with
every item in his table and to
compare whether that hash is the same as the one in his table
or not. So when he compare and choose this
record here, right. So he found oh that
hash results here, he obtained from the transmission
zone is exactly the same as the one he can see
from here, right? So then he do a reverse
lookup, OK, so reversely. Look up. So which
password can generate such a hash in this table,
OK, which is a pre-calculated table, OK,
beforehand. Then he do a reverse lookup,
he found, oh, the original password combination should be this one
which will map to this result. Then this person
can guess, oh, that's this user's password,
he used this one. And then that's why he got this hash.
Now, I stole from this transmission zone,
right? So he will do this matching uh comparison,
and then he will do a reverse lookup in his prebuild.
What we call this rainbow table, OK, prebuilt rainbow table
or um pre-computed table of hash paired with the plain
text, um, password. This is not through.
Reverse calculation because hash results is a one-way function.
You can only calculate from the left hand to the right hand,
but not calculate from the right hand to the left hand,
right, so which is actually just through uh uh reverse
lookup because they have calculated such different
combination and they all calculate this 1 to 1.
Uh, hash results, which is one-way function from left to right,
so they maintain such a 1 to 1 mapping table and
then when they got some hash stolen from online and they
will do a reverse lookup, right, and to get original
combination which can generate such a hash,
right, so this is how they do so. And, and
now currently online, OK, people don't have to generate such a
long table by themselves. What they can do is they can actually
buy this table online from the black market,
OK? And then that cost $900 US dollars each.
That's a very old price and you can check the latest price online.
You might see it cheaper. And then, and then.
It also offers um discount if you purchase
3 table um in one, in one.
Purchasing and then you can see it's a free delivery,
right, and you can get from online. So that's just a screenshot from
my um checking online and then it's a rainbow table
uh rainbow table you can purchase online which is
this combination which includes a lot of combination um of the
password and you can do this um hash mapped results in the
table. So, and in this week's workshop you can
try this rainbow table hacking, OK, through some online
available um Mapping table, OK, um,
and you can try that one and try to crack someone's password,
right? So if, which also means if you happen to use one of these
passwords which are simple combination, which can also be
easily hacked online, right, by using a free
rainbow table or sometimes purchase the rainbow table
um in those black market. So you'd better make sure
your password is very complicated, very long,
was not included in one of those tables and which can make your
um password safer, right? OK. So
one way the system is trying to fix this issue is to
provide a sorting, OK, provide sorting. So the sorting means
the hash result. will be added a sort, and then the whole result will be a
hash result and stored in the server side.
So The sorting is a random generated um
number, OK, which can, OK, you can use the 12 bits,
OK, random bits to be a sort. It can be uh 6 digits,
it can be longer, 20 digits, so it depends on how the system
um design, use, uh, how long the sort is,
right? So Uh, it's not strictly kept secret,
so which means the sort, um, you probably can see some sort results in
your Linux shadow file. You can actually see them,
right? So the 6, number 6 means a
particular hash function. Um, you can, um,
you can check what's the 6 hash uh through
Google search. You probably can
see when a hash started with a 6, which
is a 512 password hash, right, and then each
different number will give you a different hash results,
uh sorry, hash function, um it means different hash type.
And then this part dollar sign in between that's actually a sort uh used
um the hashed result of sort used for for
for this person's password and that's a sorted
password hash results, OK, um, after that one,
so. So adding some sort, which means the
same password, a random hash was added, and then,
and then the hash wouldn't be the same, right?
So if Alice and Bob, they are using the same password,
but because we have the random sort added for Alice and Bob,
so the system wouldn't generate the same hash for these two people,
right? Um, and then which fix the issue of the original
hash, uh, password results, right? We don't have to,
uh, have the same results. When we see the same hash result,
which doesn't mean the original two users are using the same password,
right? So normally they would definitely have different hash results.
We can never derive original two people are using the same password or not
because the sorting has been added. So even for the same password we,
we will have generate, we will generate a different hash results,
OK. So what sorting can do is it,
it can make rainbow table attack harder.
Why? The reason is, remember, Um,
remember, the rainbow table attack person,
right? What they, what they maintain is they maintain.
A pre-computed the table with each
combination here, right, um, and to a mapped
hash results, so it's a 1 to 1 mapping. But now because
of the sorting added so the by build up or by
pre-build by pre-build this um this
rainbow table they they know there are probably 12
digits random sort added and then for each single combination
let's see this combination is just 111 and then they have to
build. Along different results
which each one of them is a different sort.
So if we have a 12 digit sort, how many different combination of
sorts we can have? We can have 12 to 12,
sorry, 2 to 12 different combination. Right,
so which means with a simple password is uh
111 and you have added the 12 digit sort,
so which makes this many different results,
OK, because the random sort will be generated,
so there are so many different random sorts.
Uh, in here attached to this password. So then the mapped result
by adding this first random sort and we have the first mapping results
and by the second result we have another,
we have another mapped result and by another random sort we have
3, so. Each single item,
the password combination. The hacker has to maintain a
2212 different
hash results in his table, right? And then in next
different combination of the uh of the.
Password, let's say it's 112. Again, he has to
generate another 2 to 12 items.
Because 212 different sources can be added to this
single password, right? So he has to maintain another
like 2212 results, hash results in his
rainbow table. So now you can see this rainbow table will be huge,
right? So it will be 212 times of original.
Rainbow table size and considering he has to go through
every different combination when we when we do a reverse
lookup, we do reverse lookup, he has to go through
such a long table to get probably
finally original mapping, right? So which makes
this precomputation table attack.
A lot harder, right, a lot harder than before.
So your matching comparison procedure would be,
uh, taking a lot longer to do than without adding this sort.
So which is why the sorting technique. make this
precomputation attack very hard, right? However,
the sorting does not increase computational difficulty of
cracking one password. What I mean by that is you can
now imagine when you do the brute force attack,
which is to try every combination of the keyboard,
right, to go through the system. And then Even if
we add the thought, but if a hacker can guess the right combination of your
password, for example, it's 112, and he,
he can get the 112, he can still get into the system.
If he just guess, right, by brutal brute force attack to try
every combination, as long as he got the right combination,
he can pass through the system, right? No matter
what sort has been added. As long as the combination is correct,
and he can pass through the system, right?
So the sorting does not increase this computational difficulty of cracking one
password. The computational difficulty password cracking one password depends on
um how many times we can find the right combination on your keyboard.
So if the person can get the right combination,
he can always pass through the system, right?
So sorting also doesn't prevent replay attacks.
OK, so George has one question, pass the hash be used on
the web, yeah, that's right, that's what happens here in the replay attack,
right? So pass the hash, um, and then if
If a person in the transmission zone, you can imagine and such a
Sorted. Hah password was stolen
by passing the hash, OK, the man in the middle,
hacker, so he can steal the whole hash, right?
He can steal, uh, steal the whole hash results and then pass to
the system next time to the system, right?
So he gets, sorry, he steal the whole hash and they just pass the
hash to the system. And then he can get through the system,
right? So the sorting does not fix this replay attack either.
So which is why we have to consider to make sure this
hash-based authentication um more secure.
So normally by replay attack, by defending replay attack,
we would add a second. Factor such as
your six time digit code, right, or sometimes the system itself
would recognize would add a time stamp to your hash,
right, when there is a different time, the current time with the time stamp
in the hash attached to the hash. And then the system can recognize it's a wrong
logging request, right? Or if there's a second factor which is
the one time code, a six digit code has to be um the
right one and then that can also help prevent the replay attack,
but sorting doesn't itself, right? So but sorting does
make this pre-computation harder than before,
OK, um, and then I saw.
Joy's, uh, question about rocky.text. Yes,
it's the most common available rainbow table.
It's about, uh, yes, so. The
size would be, yeah, yeah, you are right,
so the size would be 133 megabytes inside,
that's a free one online and if you have to add a sort
and do a reverse look up and to calculate the pre-computation
table you have to Um, generate a
2 to 12 times 132
megabytes in size, so the size of that. Um,
pre-computation table would be huge, right,
so would make your reverse lookup and matching,
uh, comparison and reverse lookup a lot harder than before,
right, so which is why we would say, OK,
sorting does solve that rainbow table attack issue but not solve
100%. OK. It just makes your pre-computation attack a lot harder than
before and depending on how many digits of sorts were used,
OK, um. Yeah, so for
all these different type of hash, like NTLM,
12, 128, all different functions,
and as long as we got the right um rainbow table,
so that rainbow table attack attack can happen.
But adding salt is a good solution to make your pre-computation attack
a lot harder than before, OK? Butal does not solve
everything. As I said, if we can still get the right combination
by brute force attack, which means we just try every different
combination on your keyboard. If you can get the right combination,
you can still get, get through the system,
but how the system should defend against this,
this attack, right? Then this is a technique
to make sure the system is strong enough to
um defend against this brute force attack.
So, and if you have ever heard these names and then uh haven't heard them,
they are actually all based on this technique.
And these are designed protocols which define how many multiple times
of hash it should go, right, and in those protocols,
right, so it will, it's called the stretching technique or hash chain technique.
So it means The server side will not only just save
a single hash. Single hash. So it will
hash multiple times, right, and store that result in
the server side, OK. So multiple hash has been
done, right? And then you can now imagine
for For one combination, like a
111, OK, and then what the server
end is storing is um let's say just 10 times hash right
so it's a 10 times hash. Like it's 10 times of
hash. I'll just, uh, omit all this, right?
So that's 10 times high hash. So and then when you guess another
password, OK, when you guess 1112, right,
and then. The, you have to, OK, when you,
when you, when you try to crack into the system,
you have to hash 10 times, OK, and then you can then see
whether you can get through the system or not,
right. If it doesn't work and you try 113,
and then again, when you get this combination,
you again have to hash 10 times. You hash 10 times and then you
can compare with the result in the server,
but then And then the server, if it's not 113,
you have to guess 114, right? So another 10 times of hash.
So remember the hash algorithm is not simple calculation,
although a single hash can be quite quick,
but when you hash 10 times or even 20 times.
So it depends on how many, how this protocol designs,
how many times of this hash, OK, will be used in those protocols,
right? So it will reduce your guess
speed, right? So if originally you just use a single hash
on one, for example, you can guess 1 billion times per
second. With a normal GPU, right, you can guess
that many times and you can then get the right combination maybe
in about several minutes, right? So you have,
you have guessed that many times. However,
if we are using a system like Bitcrypt, right,
which was based on multiple times of hash,
which means your guessing speed is so slow.
OK, you can only guess 100 times per second,
OK, which makes your brute force attack a lot
slower. So which can guarantee the system
um not easy to be hacked, right? So because your guessing
speed is slow, you have to multiple hash for each of your
combination, right? But that multiple hash takes time which
will Largely decrease your gas speed,
right? So which makes that brute force attack a lot harder,
right? So this is how stretching techniques could help to defend against that
brute force attack, right? Now as a user,
uh, I probably will go over about a few minutes,
so I'll just keep the recording going and if you have other session please feel free to
go, otherwise you can stay here for a bit longer.
And then as a user what to do. So here I just give you some examples to,
to show you how long does it take to crack a password and how much
entropy for a for a several digit password and then they
are different, right? So the longer um the entropy.
The password has and it takes longer to crack,
right? And you can now imagine uh we have the longer passwords like
this. And it takes 1.5 years, but of course it
depends on some older computer and now even with the current um
faster GPU it's still the longer password takes longer to be correct,
right? And then I did a little bit mathematic analysis here to
calculate how many entropy, if we have either one
way to have 8 digits, OK. To have 8 digit
password, but we have more combination, including uppercase,
lowercase, and symbol and number, and so on.
Or if we have a nine-digit password, which
we don't, uh, limit the combination. Now we only use the,
the, the um upper and the lowercase of num uh letter.
OK, so then, It's um, I think a high school combination
calculation. So for nine digits, and that's how many different
combinations we could have, right? So for the first
eight digits, we can have the upper and lowercase of letter,
so which is 52, um different combination right there.
And then for the last digit here, we can have either lowercase or
upper, uppercase of letter. Or the other one is maintain the
password to be 8 digits, eight digits, but for each um
digit, we can have upper lowercase letter which is
52 different letters, or we can add 26 symbols
to make the password more complex, right?
So we just have more uh we maintain eight digit password.
But with more um combination for each letter,
OK, we have more choices. And then so that's how many different combinations we could have
with the eight digit password, but more combination,
but more uh choices for the symbol. But then this is how many different
combinations we have for nine-digit password but with only upper and
lowercases password. So this is how much entropy
each can have, like we can calculate. So,
so then that, that is how many bits of entropy,
but that will, yeah, proportional to those entropies,
right? So if it, this is longer, and this is larger and then the entropy would be bigger.
Right, so if it's smaller and then that entropy is smaller,
so larger entropy means a longer time to crack.
So if this number is larger than that one,
which means 9 digits is safer than 8 digits,
right? So through this calculation you can use a calculator.
And then this gives us the hint. Anytime the
password longer the better, OK? Because the longer always includes
more information entropy and then we, it will take longer to
crack. So Here is a hint
for the user to design your password, so we better make it,
make it longer and more complex, right? Of course,
if you can make it longer and also more complex,
then of course the password would be more safer,
right, however, to make it very complicated and it will be hard to memorize them.
So which is why this is a good way to create your password,
to, to build up some phrase that and make it,
make the phrase meaningful. Like, but you also
replace those words by some, um, number,
right, or by some symbol, OK, some, some,
some replacement only known by you, right?
And you can remember your password better,
right, rather than some random password,
OK, so make it longer also, right, as long as possible,
um. Uh, I think that the common sense is not to design a password less than
15 digits, or if you can make it longer than 20 digits,
that's even better. OK. So, so this is a,
this is a password-based authentication.
And now we have some other factors such as the factors for all,
uh, what you are, what you have, and what you have,
we here, I listed some um issues with those,
it's expensive, it's more secure, but subject to uh sift too.
And there are different types of OTP device,
one-time pad device, and then you can see it's a time-based,
uh, and also um some hash result-based uh oneTP.
So the different type of device, and then we can use them
to authenticate people, right? To prove a person
is some particular, some person. And then And then there
are also other factors like what you are,
right? So your unique property
belonging to yourself only. Like ergonomics is like your
behavior, um, analysis, right? We call that ergonomics.
However, these two are very CPU and memory intensive,
which means you have to have the scanner to scan your fingerprint.
And the CPU has to be busy with recognizing your fingerprint,
right? So it's a CPU and memory intensive and also it's
subject to those types of errors. Sometimes we got rejected by error,
we got accepted by error, so we call that false negative and false positive.
So the system always has to find a good design um to
reduce those two types of error. So, so that's more
um resource intensive for this what you are factor.
And then the people, when they design a more secure protocol,
they sometimes would design a protocol based on your password and your
pin code, which is probably um six digit time code,
right? And then, or sometimes it define um the user password or
your face recognition, like those kind of multi-factor
authentication. And the people always find the password are really
uh causing problem. Um, the world is over reliance,
reliant on password. So there's um alliance,
which actually designed some other um protocol,
which they, through which they try to discuss password and try to use a
different way to authenticate people, right?
And then here is a summary about uh all my discussion with
this authentication. If it's a password,
Um, plain password is not good if it's a password over and encrypted,
but there's still a lot of problem. And if you use a single hash of
a password but vulnerable to rainbow table attack,
but if we use a sorted, it makes the rainbow table attack a lot
harder but still vulnerable to brute force attack,
right? So then the people use stretching technique to prevent.
The brute force attack and also the replay,
uh oh sorry, yeah, to, to, to prevent the brute force attack.
But however, this still has the replay attack,
so that's why people are using multi-factor authentication,
right? So. Um And then, and then
they use some protocol, right? The protocol,
the one we will try in our workshop is to,
uh, is not to use password at all. So we use a public and
private key-based authentication, which is again based on RSA algorithm we have
learned in last week, right? So there are also some other
protocol, um, you can explore maybe um
If you're interested in authentication, there are other protocols which were based on,
not based on password at all. OK. So here are all about this
week's study. Um, so I, I wish you would have fun in your
workshop. So that's all for today. Thank you.